Hello, I'm your host David Bernard and
with me today, Revenue Cat CEO, Jacob
Biding. Our guest today is Eric Duffett,
a high school teacher and indie app
developer. Eric is a founder of Shop
Pattern, a golf GPS app focused on
strategy. On the podcast, we talk with
Eric about his journey from failed first
app to success with his second, the
advantages of building for problems
people are already talking about, and
why he turned down a lucrative
acquisition offer to keep building. Hey,
Eric, thanks so much for joining us on
the podcast today.
Yeah, thank you for having me. Uh, I've
listened to every single episode, so I'm
incredibly humbled to be on this side of
the speaker.
Are you going to listen to this one?
This might be the one I skip.
Okay,
we'll see.
And Jacob, always nice to have you.
That's great. I unlike Eric, I've I've
never listened to an episode of Sub
Club. So, a complete opposite. I've just
been almost
All right. Well, I've been super excited
to talk to you, Eric. You were on a blog
post. You collaborated on a blog post
about not selling your app, and that
kind of like introduced me to you and
like what you've been working on. I
wanted to step back and you are a high
school teacher that built an app as a
side project like how did that happen
and and and yeah tell us a little bit
about the the beginning story.
Yeah, more than one app as a side
project and the first one went very
different than the second. So I'm a high
school teacher. I teach business and app
development actually at an amazing
Chicago area high school. And back in
2015, I had an idea for an app and no
money to pay anybody to build it for me.
And I said, well, I'll just learn how to
code and figure it out myself. So, I
spent about I don't know 3 months on a
Udemy course. Luckily, and
coincidentally, my high school sent me
to a boot camp called Mobile Makers.
They actually train high school teachers
how to teach app development. And so it
just a really lucky break. They give me
the building blocks to just understand
the basics because before that it was
just like copy paste and like oh I think
it works. And from there I started
building a meditation app for golfers.
As a high school coach I had seen my
athletes struggle and I felt like they
needed something to deal with the
adversity they were facing in their
sport. Many of them were pursuing
college scholarships. So I thought like
hey I see a problem. I see that you're
struggling and I I have a way to help
you and I want to build something that
can help you perform better like build
resilience, build some mental hygiene
and mental skills. And so I started
creating that app for them.
I'm smiling ear to ear right now because
like the uh my whole thesis with
RevenueCat is there's like a million
billion niches that need to be filled
with software and meditation for golfers
hadn't been one that even crossed my
mind. So, did you start thinking about
the app and working on the app before
the school thought they would want you
to teach app development or or like what
was the order there? Because I I missed
that when we were talking about this
before. Yeah, they came online about the
same time. I knew that it was becoming
easier to build apps. I think Swift as a
language was very new at that point. I
was aware of the mobile makers
organization and at the same time I knew
I wanted to build for myself. And so I
basically got a head start while I was
waiting on the school to figure out if
we're going to adopt the curriculum and
create the class. I'm just like, I'm
just going to figure this out and then
if I happen to go to training, that'll
be a bonus.
That's so cool. So then how did things
go with that first app? I believe it's
called Undaunted Golf.
That's right. Yeah, it was a a lesson in
what product market fit isn't. Um
that's that's most lessons in product
market fit are.
Um, like I said, I had I had seen my
athletes struggling. I knew that they
needed help. And it took me basically 5
years from having the idea to realizing
I was wrong to get to the point where I
actually sat down with them and asked
them, hey, like I I saw this moment in
time. Tell me about it. And when they
talked to me, it's like I guess it was
hard, but like I don't know. There's
essentially what they said. And they had
never looked for a solution. They never
tried to buy anything. They never
downloaded anything. They never asked
for help. There was no purchasing intent
or really problem to solve in their
eyes. And throughout that 5 years, I had
emailed every single college golf coach
in the country. Two of them told me I
needed to be on Android. So, I built an
Android app. I had worked with the
design team to like redesign the app. I
I sat in my closet for months on end
recording all of these audio scripts and
inspirational messages and meditations.
And then I like again basically five
years where I I get to the end and like
hey do you want this? And they not
really. And along the way there were
some signs that other people may have
wanted it. I got a couple messages from
50 60 year old men who really liked the
app. I got a couple of coaches who again
are adults that really like the app. But
because I was so focused on that initial
hypothesis I completely missed it. And
when I conducted those user interviews
and they said hey we don't really want
this. I was like, "All right, that's
that's it for me as an indie. Like, I'm
moving on. If I'm going to make money
with apps, it's going to be because I do
contract work or somebody pays me to
write code. Like, this indie thing is
just not for me."
It's such a such a good highlight that
like learning to build an app is a one
thing, but like building a product is a
whole another discipline. They're
sometimes interrelated and often you can
be good at both, but like they're not
necessarily the same thing. and like
one's more human and more data driven
and you know the other is you know more
technical but I heard so many stories
it's really an interesting thing it's
often too like the first time somebody
builds something that they like they get
it in their crawl they believe it's
going to be real and then I don't know
if maybe some combination of some cost
fallacy and just like belief and just
like naive but this is not the first
time I've seen somebody go a long time
on something that never really had legs
it's not uncommon
what did you do with that app to to
market it and how many downloads did you
even end up getting in those 5 years?
Yeah. So marketing at first I thought
like if you publish the app store like
if you build it they will come and they
didn't come. There was all sorts of
issues related to that and like I said I
was like all right I need to to push
harder. I need to put myself out there.
So I got the email address of every
single college golf coach in the
country. I emailed every single one
which is over 300 I'm fairly certain and
about five responded and two just wrote
back unsubscribe. It it wasn't even like
a subscription. I I literally copy
pasted every single one so you couldn't
unsubscribe. It wasn't a mailing list.
And one wrote back this really mean
email. And like I said, two wrote back,
"Hey, I need you to be on Android." And
I thought like, "Oh, this is this is the
secret unlock." And beyond that, I tried
some really weak efforts at Twitter ads
and that was really it.
Yeah. And I think it's the coral, like
you said, it's what product market fit
isn't. It's like if you don't have a
kernel of something of a product and and
maybe you kind of highlighted it maybe
if you had leaned into the couple of
people that had wrote in and like you
know whatever but it seems like c
talking to customers was you know came
later which is like especially in BTOC I
think not done enough is like talking
like talking to it's too easy to like
you said just put it on the app store
not anonymously but almost anonymously
and then people download it somewhat
anonymously and then you never have to
interact with another human As nice as
that can be for nerds, it's so valuable
to like talk to these people, right? And
you learn a lot about what you're doing
and what you're not doing and why
they're actually using it or not using
it. So,
did you end up doing any consulting or I
know you ended up building another app?
Did you just jump right into that next
app and and why did you decide to keep
going on a second app after that first
experience? So I developed a love for
building apps and I stumbled into a
problem at the high school that I teach
at and and I built an app for the high
school and then people saw it and they
asked for a couple more. So I started
doing side projects, consulting work.
They paid me just a little and then as a
second kid came along as I need to make
more money. I did pick up some contract
work. I even applied for some jobs as a
software engineer cuz the salary ceiling
is much higher. And so I was looking for
ways to monetize my ability to make apps
and just kind of stumbled into my app
shop pattern. It was meant to be just
for me. As I started building it, I like
the way it looked and then I was like,
well, maybe I can make a little money
off this. My goal was to make $1,000 a
summer just to justify spending money on
golf. Like, hey, like if I can have one
hobby, pay for the other hobby, it's a
wash. Like that's that's all I need. I
found it really easy to implement
revenue cap. I was like, "All right,
I'll I'll throw it in the app store.
This is not going to take over my life
like the last one did. It is just going
to passively sit there and if it makes
money, great. But I'm not making the
same mistake I made first time."
What was the idea behind the second app
and how is it different from the first?
Yeah, so shot pattern was born out of my
obsession with golf. I had been
listening to golf podcasts and learning
from golf experts. And essentially
there's this idea, this methodology of
like perfecting golf strategy where you
need to go on the course and you need to
measure side to side how much room there
is to like land your golf ball. And I'll
I'll try to keep it in non-golfer terms.
And the brilliant people behind like all
of the math for how to do this were just
like, "Hey, you need to go on Google
Maps. you need to use the measuring tool
on Google Maps on the satellite image
and you can measure side to side on the
course. And they had created this
behavior where people were going online
and measuring the golf course. And I was
like them. I was like having a lot of
fun measuring golf courses via the
satellite images. But then I get out
onto the golf course and I of course
wasn't disciplined enough to take paper
notes or do anything with me. And so I
was like, wait, everything's a little
bit different than what I thought it
would be. So I just wanted something
real time. Let me measure the hole in
front of me. Let me see what the
analytics say in terms of proper
strategy. It was a little toy for myself
at first to just make that process of
understanding golf strategy in real time
easier. This was already kind of a a
thing, right? And maybe that's what's a
little bit different from your first app
and then this app is that you kind of
latched on to something that influencers
were already talking about in the golf
space that like there was already some
kind of motion behind this idea and then
your app I assume just kind of made it
easier.
Yeah, exactly. So the creator of this
way of thinking, his name's Scott
Faucet. He had been teaching
professional golfers. He had his name
mentioned on golf broadcasts. He had
this basically system that he was
teaching people for at least 5 years
prior to the launch of shot pattern. And
so yeah, he had he had already created
the behavior change of this is the way
you need to prepare for a round of golf,
prepare for a golf tournament, how to
think about it when you're on the
course. And so all of these people, all
of the content marketing of this is
something you should be doing to play
better had been done for years in
advance of my app hitting the app store.
And that was, yeah, like you said, a
huge difference in me trying to force a
new behavior upon people to just giving
them an easier way to do what they
already wanted to do.
It's it's way easier to write a trend
than to than to create a trend, right?
So, you launched the app. How did things
go? And did it look super different in
those early days from the early days of
Undaunted?
Yeah, I mean almost right away it looked
different in that one I I was doing more
content marketing up front. I knew not
to have the mindset if you build it they
will come. So I built the social media
presence a week or two before the launch
before the app was ready and just
started putting content out there
engaging in conversations and I
continued that after the launch
but only like a week or two before.
That's actually I would say pretty
pretty short. You know, sometimes you
can see people build an audience like
months before a launch of something.
Well, I mean, I built the first version
of the app in three weeks. So, talk
about night and day differences. Five
years of of turmoil versus like 3 weeks
to V1 like I'm going to put on the app
store. Even though
it's not it's not the the myth of like
get rich quick is not true, but it is
kind of true because like often you do
something that's not super valuable for
a long time until you figure out the
thing that is valuable and then that is
very quick. So in theory, you could have
jumped directly to that, but like that's
sort of in theory, right? But often when
the thing hits, it's fast, right?
Yeah. So I had a little bit of a social
media presence. I put the app out there.
I start talking about it on Twitter
where a lot of golfers like me are
hanging out, engaging in conversations
and and I noticed that every time I
added value to the community and dropped
some screenshots in there, like I'd see
a couple trial starts hit. And so it
just slowly ticking up. Slowly ticking
up. I got a few direct messages from
professional golfers on the very
beginner level tours. I didn't have to
work that hard to get the first
downloads to see early signs of
monetization. And honestly, one of the
best signs that something was working
was that people were paying for it that
I never heard from. I knew my like four
customers before like, oh, like, yeah,
there's Norm again. Uh, but this time
people were paying me and I never
interacted with them. I was like, this
is not the same as before. This is
working. And so in those early days, I
know you had a few kind of key decision
points of like, okay, it's working, but
like to take it to the next level, you
really needed to start investing into
it. What What happened there?
Yeah. So, like I said, the the first
version was built in basically 3 weeks
from first line of code to on the app
store. And so, it was very very bare
bones. And in order to professionalize
it and get it anywhere close to what
people were expecting, I needed some
golf course data. It needed to be aware
of like where the T- box was, where the
green was, point you in the right
direction, like know how many holes were
on the course because prior to that, it
was just the satellite image from Apple
Maps. Wherever you pulled it up, it
would like just treat it as a golf
course. And I poked around and the only
way to get this data from a reliable
provider was to pay $5,000 upfront. And
I was like, "Oh, like you can't do this
again. You got a kid on the way. Like
you you told yourself you weren't going
to go down this path and it's like a bad
ex-girlfriend like calling you back.
I've changed." I went to my wife and she
gave me some really like sage advice. I
guess it was more of a question, but
she's like, "Is this a hobby or is it a
business?" And to me, what that meant
was, again, a hobby is something you
spend time on and you spend money on
because you enjoy it. And a business is
something that actually makes money. And
you have to do all the parts. You don't
get to just do the fun parts. You don't
get to work on it just when you feel
like it. It's it's there. It's something
that needs your investment. And so I had
to decide like, is this going to be
something that I treat like more like a
job or is this going to be something
that I have fun with? Does your wife
happen to also be a tax accountant? Cuz
because there are some like filing
differences between Maybe that's what
she was talking about.
Um I think she had seen me struggle and
justify spending time on something that
wasn't going anywhere and was just kind
of sick of it.
It's literally the tax code, right? Is
like when something's a hobby versus,
you know, and it's a gray it's a gray
line, but I do think if not having
clarity there is a problem.
Yeah, absolutely. And I think she was
just like, "What are we doing here?" and
kind of tapped out from the first
experience. But I decided to go for it
to pay the $5,000 to basically go four
grand into the negatives uh at that
point. And I was playing golf the next
day after like sending the money over
and having buyer remorse and and I was
joking with my buddy who knew what was
going on. I was like, "Man, I I didn't
want to pay a hundred bucks for somebody
else's golf app, but now I'm four grand
in the hole." But that that turned out
to be like an amazing decision in two
ways. One, it put a ton of pressure on
me to like take a big swing at this and
to figure out a way to get back into the
black because this wasn't something that
I could afford to lose money on. And the
other thing, like once I said yes to
that small snippet of of functionality
that I thought I needed, I was digging
into the APIs to figure out what else
was there to like really take advantage
of the money I'd spent. And I found
something else that I didn't know I had
purchased that unlocked this additional
behavior that nobody else was doing. And
so I started working on it and thinking
about it. And it was another idea that a
brilliant statistician had popularized.
he wrote about in a book like in the
early 2000s and I was like I think I can
do that via an app and it doesn't have
to only live in your supercomput. And so
what I did was I basically was able to
take a user's data and reflect it back
to them and show them an expected value
of any shot that they hit. And that was
something that apparently people were
really excited about cuz I put it in a
tweet and it just blew up more than
anything else I had done. And it was at
that point where things really started
to change once I put a teaser out there
for like, hey, I'm I'm in the middle of
building this and it's going to be
really cool and I think you guys are
going to like it and a whole bunch of
people shared it and after that I was
getting phone calls from influencers and
business owners and that was the thing
that was sent things off to the races.
Is there like golf Twitter? Is this like
in golf Twitter? Is that where like cuz
I don't think it would go viral on my
Twitter. No, it would not go viral on
yours, but yes, there's golf Twitter and
there's a handful of us that hang out
there and Yeah, exactly. And so it was
this community that I was a part of
before as a regular person and had
learned what I needed to know, like what
inspired me to build the app and then
just kept on like taking these ideas
from Golf Twitter, from the content
creators and and figuring out how to
make them into an app. It's so
interesting like people are so much more
receptive to things built by insiders
for them. Do you know what I mean? Like
this we call it community, right? But I
think there is this like a new product
is such a big
risk. Not really, but I think people,
you know, it takes a lot. You're not
going to pay 100 bucks for somebody's
random app, right? But when somebody's
from your community and they speak like
you and they understand your problems,
that I think is such a big bridge. And
these are small time kind of gorilla
marketing things like you know you
wouldn't think of like an app scaling
through just tweets you know when you're
going at the very beginning it's
certainly something right it builds a
ground swell builds that base
right exactly and I and I knew that I
didn't have the money to do paid so I
was whatever I could do just to have a
little sweat equity to again to build
the content marketing to engage in
conversation every little piece was
basically free money it was just effort
at that point that took the the value ad
to the community and turned it into a
couple of subscribers and things just
kept ticking in the right direction.
And now you can do what I do, which is,
"Honey, I'm posting for work. It's work.
I have to be on Twitter at this family
engagement wherever we are."
Yeah. It doesn't go over real well. So,
I'm I'm happy to have found another way
to grow the app.
Were you posting this from a personal
account or he cuz I've seen your Shop
Pattern account. Were you building all
of this on the shop pattern account or
your personal account?
Uh, yeah, the shop pattern account. So,
like everything lived there and and I
toggle between the Wii and the I and I
never know which one to use or whether
to use a pronoun at all. But yeah, just
like everything came from Shop Pattern
and said, "Hey, this feature is coming
soon." And I teased it out there well
before it was done. And and I knew that
it was I was heading in the right
direction.
It's so funny when David told me you
were on the show, all I could think of
is the Shop Pattern logo cuz that's who
you are on Twitter. Like exactly. Yeah.
Very funny.
How many followers did you have at that
point? I mean, I'm just kind of curious
like for people listening, building in
these niche communities, it's just such
a great story that like finding this
niche, finding product that has pull in
the market instead of having to push it
into the market. And then, you know, I
would guess it it wasn't a massive
following that that allowed this to
start getting traction. So, how many
followers did you have when you tweeted
out those that new feature you were
building?
Yeah, I I still only have about 2,600.
So, I I might have had a thousand and
the tweet did again relative to
everything else did 25 or 40,000
impressions. Um, was shared by several
people and like I said, I had a number
of people send me direct messages like,
"Hey, I would love to talk just like
meet you and and see who you are." And
one of the people who interacted with
that, saw it, was somebody who
downloaded the app, won a golf
tournament the next day in part because
they used it and eventually that turned
into discussions for them being
interested in buying the app as I wrote
about in the blog.
Right. Well, yeah. So, tell us that
story. So, yeah. So, you're still early.
The app hasn't made a ton of money, but
it's showing these signs of product
market fit and somebody offered to just
buy it outright.
Yeah. So they called me up. We had a
meeting. And our first meeting was
supposed to be basically the minute my
daughter was born. And so I I emailed
them at at midnight the night before
like, "Hey, I I think I'm going to have
to reschedule." So we we chat a couple
weeks later and they say, "Hey, we
really like it. We were thinking of
building something like that ourselves,
but we really like what you put together
and yeah, we'd like to buy it from you."
And I was ecstatic for 10 seconds and I
realized, wait a second, like I don't
have a whole lot to go on in terms of
what this app could be worth. And they
asked me to put together a a slide deck
mainly on the technology that I had used
like my tech stack and then they wanted
to know download numbers and like number
of users.
Can you describe like the nature of the
buyer? I signed an NDA, so I don't want
to go into too much detail, but it was a
tangential golf business.
They had been in apps before, like they
had some awareness of apps, I guess.
Yeah, they had awareness of apps. They
they had their own app. They saw this at
I guess you would call it a strategic
acquisition. This wasn't a financial
buyer with like an app shop. This was
somebody who said, "Hey,
that's kind of what I was wondering."
Yeah.
Yeah. Exactly. They had asked for me to
put together a couple of slides of like,
"Hey, how many downloads do you have?"
And I had listened to the subscription
apps report podcast and look at the
reports maybe a month before that. And
so I like I don't want to go on
downloads. It's still like almost
nothing. Like let me figure out what I
can do here to show you just how well
this app is performing. And so I put
together my slides and so I'm like
pulling up this the trial start
benchmarks and I like whoa I'm at 25%
and then trial conversion I'm at 75% and
I'm looking at the chart and it's like
it's off the charts in terms of
performance trial the paid of 17%. And
this is an organic audience and there's
there's some juicing of the numbers
because of where the downloads came
from. But still, as I'm putting this
together, I'm realizing like this has
some serious potential. And it's really
hard to to put a number on exactly what
this could be. Talked to a handful of
people. I talked to very good ventures
who I I know you you guys know them over
there and said, "Hey, what would you pay
to build this?" And they didn't say
exactly, but they gave me a ballpark
range that was helpful. I talked to a
handful of other people to try to get
some advice about exactly what kind of a
number to put on it. and I put a big
number out there and they came back with
like final offer of 75,000. I sat with
that for a while and it's like okay I
can cash in a a sure thing and like get
a little bit of cushion back or I can
keep building cuz I think I can do that.
One thing that terrified me was in the
the back and forth they had said like we
just put this on our road map we are
going to build it and kind of left some
blank space there. So read between the
lines. Either you sell it to us or we
crush you. And that part was really
intimidating to me. And I reached out to
the sub club community online uh
community that you guys have put
together and just said, "Hey, so people
are are offering to buy my app, but I
don't really have any numbers to create
a valuation with. Anybody out there gone
through this or can somebody help me?"
And Seth Miller of Raphat chimed in and
he sent me a message like, "Hey, give me
a call." And as we were talking, I was
going through this. He asked me all
these questions just so that I could
understand how I felt about it. And I
said, "But Seth, like they said that
they're just going to build this and
crush me." And nobody has ever said the
f-word on the Subub podcast to my
knowledge, and I don't want to be the
first. Um, but Seth basically said,
"Well, f them. Like, let them try." And
I'm so appreciative of him just like
giving that me that little jolt of
confidence to be like, "You know what?
like you built something meaningful.
Like somebody can't just roll out of bed
and and put this together. It's going to
take effort and even though you used AI,
like there's still something here. A
couple things I've experienced and seen
and whatever on that is like yes, that's
right. Like you might have been through
similar situations with him and I'm not
sure, but like the one that's always
used when somebody's trying to buy
something cuz it's like you're usually
being acquired by a larger bigger, you
know, somebody with deep pockets. So
they probably have a little bit of
leverage or whatever and and they're
doing a bill versus buy discussion
unless it's like a PE app thing you're
just like flipping it for the cash flow
but like but usually so that will always
come up as a way to like sort of you
know encourage you to to do the deal for
that same reason is the threat is almost
like if if they were so motivated and so
good and able to build this thing they
probably just would have built it right
but they didn't you did um and and so
because of that I think it's a bluff
usually worth calling usually Not
always. Like you probably come up
negative on that a few times because
that's just the nature of why you do a
strategic acquisition, right? You don't
do it for no reason. But then also like
companies I think it tend to be kind of
opportunistic. You know what I mean? So
it's like they see this app, they maybe
could get it for cheap. They maybe kind
of are interested in doing it, but like
it's not like the people that are going
to work on an acquisition are the same
people who would build it, right? So
it's not like, oh, we're not going to do
the acquisition, so let's go build those
same people on building it, right? It's
like different resources of the company.
So it's not always like lock and step
like this. So, lots of reasons why if
you hear that threat, whatever you want
to call it, you should do exactly what
you did, which is like take a minute.
Kind of creates a similar pressure to
buying the database, right? It's like,
okay, if I say no to this, it's almost
like you you walked away from a $75,000
windfall. You're like, okay, I got to
make more than $75,000 now or like this
was a big mistake.
And that's exactly what happened next. I
had a high for I don't know like two
weeks because the the day that I walked
away from those negotiations, uh, Golf
Digest called and did a little
interview. I was like, I'm off to the
races without them. Like, this is great.
And then the weather turns and
everything slows down. And and then I
hit reality of like, oh my goodness. And
I I do my taxes actually and I look at
what I actually made. I'm like, okay, at
this rate it will take me 75 years to
make that money back. Um, and I go from
like elation to this even greater sense
of loss aversion than I had the first
time. And there were multiple times
where I essentially had breakdowns or or
near panic attacks that I' like, what
have I done? Like I'm have so much work
ahead of me. I don't know how I'm
possibly going to catch up to that
number. Meanwhile, I still feel like I
have this ghost chasing me of like if I
don't figure out how to make the app
even better, they're just going to
replicate it and I'm gone. And again
during that time another indie developer
was such a huge resource for me. I had
heard Curtis Herberts from Slopes on
your podcast. I went over and I listened
to like basically all of his episodes on
independence and I had listened to his
story of how he built slowly over time
and I said Curtis this happened. I'm
having major regrets. Should I just sell
the app or what's even possible here? Is
like this is this a realistic number for
me to reach in the next 3 years? And of
course he couldn't answer that. But he
did give me the the calm and the
guidance of just like, hey, you don't
even know if you would have had that
money in the bank account. There's a
good chance they're going to try to
retrade it after due diligence or during
due diligence anyway. And so, don't get
too attached to the number. Just build
when you can. Give yourself some grace.
You'll have the summer and just slowly
plot along and see what happens. But you
don't have to do all of this at once.
And again, don't get too attached to
what you think you for sure had if you
had said yes. That got me to step away
from the ledge and like, all right, I'm
just going to do what I can and there's
doesn't need to feel like a a race that
I can never win. And I just got to
plotting and building and adding
features to the app that allow me to
raise the price and better support my
users and give them more of what they
already wanted. And so I just kept
plugging away, plugging away. And it
took me until basically the end of June,
that following summer, to release an
updated version that allowed me to
charge about double what I was charging
before. So now the price is 75 bucks a
year. Then I started paid marketing. And
that's when again I made another jump
because of the marketing efforts.
When they first approached you, you were
barely in the market, right? You barely
made any money. You really didn't have
any like longitudinal data. than to like
wait an entire year later and to even
just to see a second data point like I
can do things and I can like increase
something right now you have maybe the
same conversation come up you'd be much
more equipped to understand like what
that process looks like I think a lot of
people go through this especially with
compounding businesses is that in the
moment the week to week can look very
flat or very erratic it has to be looked
at almost in in years to really
understand like okay is there a
compounding motion here and like
Curtis's business is a great example cuz
like super seasonal as I imagine you
guys are too and especially in seasonal
businesses you don't see it because you
have these massive like seasonal spikes
and decays and like the emotions of like
oh I made you know onetenth of what I
made in peak season last month has got
to really drive you nuts but you have to
look at June over June you know like to
really see a signal was it pretty flat
that whole time so like from the turning
down the acquisition was money just like
barely trickling in and you were just
like ah crap for like nine months.
Yeah. And so I wouldn't say nine months,
but so I I say no in October and then
November, December, January, February,
things are are Yeah. going down. So
monthly is basically all all abandoned.
A few new users trickle in. And now I'm
so busy building that I've really
stopped marketing. And so now that's
really weighing on me like, how do I
spend my time? How do I do all of this?
I still have at this point like a four
or fivemonth-old daughter. I I have a
full-time job and I just like feeling
like I have taken on too much. Then the
weather starts to warm up. Some
connections I made through the the
Twitter community. People who already
had an audience are say positive things
about me online and and March is great
and April's better and now I'm seeing
things pick back up and there's there's
signs of hope. There's there's a light
at the end of the tunnel as I'm
finishing up building these these new
features.
And so then you released a big update in
June and and then as you said started
market in July. How did things go?
Yeah. So again that loss aversion, that
pressure of like I have to get to this
number or else I'm going to feel
terrible.
It stinks that that works so well for
me. I don't want to go back there, but
it really works. So I was like, I have
to take a swing at paid in order to hit
this number. Uh so I tried I I listened
to the podcast. I knew I needed to spend
a considerable amount in order to like
get the machine to start working. I
tried an image only campaign for a
couple of weeks. It didn't really go
anywhere. It was about break even. And
then I was like, "All right, I I need to
try video and it's not really my skill
set." I'd been reaching out to uh video
creators saying like, "Hey, here's a
free version of the app. Would love if
you talked about it." Many of them were
just willing to to send out an odd post
like, "Hey, I'm just trying out this new
app." But a couple of them came back and
said, "I would love to put together a
video, but it's going to cost money."
So, I paid two creators. One, I paid I
think 750 bucks because his follower
count was somewhat small. And another
one was a creator who had done really,
really, really well on TikTok who had
this really unique approach and he said,
"Hey, I'm going to enter this golf
tournament. I want you to sponsor me.
I'll put together a video for you." And
he asked for $1,500.
I thought with his audience that he
would likely pay that back pretty
quickly because he was getting 50,000
100,000 views on every Tik Tok that that
would be the secret unlock. But then I
only had two videos. So I had to make at
least one more just to fill out the ad
set. So very quickly, just so I could
get the campaign up and running, I was
like, "All right, let me do a screen
recording." So I just pull up the app. I
do a screen recording with the first
idea that comes to mind. I download Cap
Cut and like let it do its thing to make
some captions and like throw it in the
ads set of like all right now I got
three now it can run and now this this
guy I had to pay all the money to like
now that ad can go work and I hit go and
I I wake up a couple days later and I'm
like rubbing my eyes and looking at my
stats and like wait a second wait this
is this right? I'm getting installs for
like 70 cents with this ad. And I'm
looking and it's coming from the one
that I made in my basement when I was in
a hurry that I check my revenue
dashboard and I look at like my average
revenue per download is in the 350 to $4
range and my installs are.7.
Like I didn't know this was possible
anymore. I thought this went away with
AT. Like I'm minting money. So like off
I run to the bank. I tell my wife like,
"Hey, I'm opening up a line of credit."
She's like, "You're doing what?" Like
don't worry, you'll be fine.
Jeez.
Um, I ended up getting an interest free
credit card, but like I did everything I
could to maximize.
That's still credit, by the way. That's
still leverage. I just want you to know
just cuz there's no interest rate, you
still owe that money. There's still risk
there.
Yeah. Felt like like how can I just push
this as far as it'll go like into the
summer and like with the spend. And so
basically thanks to that last second ad,
um the revenues from last year, so 2024
ended up being about 185,000. I was able
to pay myself $100,000. Like took it all
out of the business and just said, I did
it. I beat the number that they put in
front of me. Like I can't believe that
this is how it all came together. But it
was a huge monkey off my back to say
like, "All right, we did it. Now we can
just focus on like building and slowly
growing and like having some fun without
uh feeling like there's these numbers
haunting you in the background.
That's really good. That's really great
to like be in the green again. You know
what I mean? They always were, right?
But to like be mentally past the
checkpoint. I always This is somewhat
similar, but whenever we raise money,
they increase the valuation rate and I'm
always like gosh like now the
valuation's way ahead of our multiple
like whatever. And I always feel better
once like we're out ahead again. And I'm
like, "Yeah." You know, uh, which is
kind of a a mental hack, too, to like
force us to like keep pushing cuz it's
like, okay, we kind of wrote a check and
like we had to work to be able to cash
it, you know?
That's exactly what I felt. And I'm
trying to figure out what to do with
that now that there's not really a
number sitting out there. But it's kind
of, like you said, a helpful mental hack
to to have to push for something and to
figure out a way to get there. And yeah,
like I said, just an incredible
experience to have gotten over the hump
and to to now be where I'm at today.
What a cool story, too. I mean, as a as
a full-time teacher, you made a 100K on
the side hustling an app in the summer,
nights and weekends, and like what a
great thing. Yeah, I love being able to
talk to my students about it. I try to
find the balance of like how much do I
share, what numbers do I share, how do
how much do I work in my experience? But
yeah, I feel like an adjunct professor
sometimes of like, hey, here's here's
how it goes in the real world. It's
really improved my teaching. It brings
the classroom to life and and helps me
add some humility into my teaching as
well because I'm supposed to be the
person who like has all of the right
answers. But when we do our social media
advertising work, it's like, okay, if
you post it and it does well, then
whatever I was going to give you as a
grade is out the window. Like, I'm not
the one who decides. The market decides.
So, I was I was wrong about my own
stuff. So, I can't possibly know for
certain that that
we just do the rest of the podcast on
business education because like I think
this is like something that MBAs suffer
from, you know, not all of them. I've
had to go to meet, but I think when you
get an NBA, they're like, I went to
business school so they taught me all
the things to do in business and it's
like that's not possible. Like that's
not a thing that exists, right? Like
maybe you read some case studies, you
saw some things that didn't work, but
like the only reality exists in the
market, right? Like that's the only
thing that's real.
Yeah. Exactly. And that's what I I try
to teach them and give them the the
freedom to to prove me wrong if I have
critical things to say about their work
or or or just to to try to get the real
feedback rather than the teacher
feedback, pushing them towards not just
playing school, but actually learning by
doing. That's my my favorite way to
teach a class.
A
as you and I were prepping for the
podcast, I I asked you this question and
I thought your answer was fantastic. So,
I want to ask you, you know, the the app
has been doing better and better, and
this year looks like it's going to be
even better than last year. And clearly,
you've built something people want now.
So, when are you going to quit teaching?
I know it's it's a fair question. Um,
one, if I didn't work at potentially the
best high school in the country, I'd
probably already be out of there. The
students I have are amazing. They love
to learn. I get paid really well. the
colleagues that I have again because
it's a high-paying school attracts tons
of great talent and so I I work with
really impressive people who are
inspiring to be alongside and I like my
job. I was not looking to get away from
teaching. We're getting to a point where
I I should seriously consider it. I'm
past 500,000 in ARR.
I'm probably going to do over 500
$600,000 in sales and half of that's
going to be net profit for the year. And
so it's becoming a a very real
possibility that not is this something I
could do but almost something I should
do to be like financially responsible to
myself. But my biggest worry
is uh that my relationship to the work
will change dramatically. That like to
go from like this is fun money. This is
extra for my family that's going to help
us have a cushion to now when I wake up
every day like if I see the numbers this
week is worse than last week. I'm afraid
that I will never sleep again because I
am so worried that all of this is gonna
disappear from underneath me. And I've
already felt that when it's on the side
and I am just terrified that if if it
becomes the only thing, then like I
said, I will I will stop enjoying it and
it will just haunt me that I can never I
I'm just waiting for it to fall apart.
Are you at the point where your time is
a constraint on growth? Like at some
point it's not even about the cash flow.
there there's a cash flow in like right
time investment or whatever but like are
you at the point where you don't think
the like nights and weekends can get you
to the next level anymore or like where
are you in that journey are you still
working solo what's the situation
yeah so I do everything by myself I do
pay some content creators to help me
create content both goes to their
audience but I repurpose it as ads so
that's been a helpful way to start
basically having other people work on my
behalf but I I still yeah my time is a
constraint because I'm the only
developer. I'm the only marketer and I
basically choose between the two and
customer support is 30 minutes in the
morning and 30 minutes at night.
That might be something you could bring
somebody in to help with, right? A
little bit easier than maybe the coding
or marketing and stuff like that. But
but then again, you're now starting to
build a real business. Like even that
changes the relationship to it, right?
Yeah. It's funny too when you and I were
talking, you know, I was telling you my
experience with almost the exact
opposite is that I spent 12 years had
four kids during the time running my
indie app business with constant
existential dread
and then I got a job at Revenue Cat. And
there there really is something too. The
grass is always greener and like for me
it has been really nice and my wife even
commented after I had joined been at
Revenue Cat like a year. She's like,
"Wow, your your like your base stress
has gone down noticeably
and a valid worry like when it is your
own thing that this is how you provide
for your family is this app and there's
going to be competitors. There's going
to be market shifts like the ad spend
might break and you might up 30K that
you're not getting a return on." And I
thought about like, oh, do I just raise
money to give myself a cushion to grow
it? And again, I guess I've realized
that I don't want to have a boss in
this. And so I'm I'm happy to bootstrap
and we'll we'll keep it this way. And
and whether or not to go full-time on
the app is a question I'll have to
answer. And luckily, even if my boss
listens to this, he already knows that
things are going really well. So he's
not going to be too upset with me.
It's a great question to be presented
with. It's kind of funny. I wonder if
there's going to be any sour grapes from
listeners who are like want this
opportunity so bad and then like you get
it and like you're not even sure. But
that's how it happens sometimes, right?
I think sometimes I see in the indie
hacker community maybe like a too much
of an obsession with the outcome which
is like financial freedom or whatever
and less of a less of a focus on just
the craft like building for people and
enjoying the process and like all that
stuff. And I think you're probably more
likely to be successful. Maybe it's 51
49, but like I think you're more likely
to be successful if you're not doing it
necessarily for the money, right? Or
necessarily for the like lifestyle quote
unquote. um you're doing it for the love
of doing it and then uh and for the fun
and then eventually like you're probably
more likely to to get there and like
I don't think the assets any less
valuable or interesting as an
acquisition opportunity now probably
right so even more so and even probably
easier to price at this point right now
that you've got a couple years of data
so I think they're all good options uh
from where I'm sitting so
congratulations
yeah and I just want to like turn it
back to you and say thank you to Revenue
Cat because uh I really look at what
you've built as one of the only reasons
why this is even possible from like can
I even build something with
subscriptions the first time it didn't
have subscriptions because it was too
hard and like oh a day to implement
revocat that's that's super easy and
then for to know I was making money to
turn down that initial offer because I
saw the state of subscription apps
report and where I was against the
benchmarks and to bet on myself to
knowing I was running profitable ads
throughout the journey
revenue cap was there to like help
support me and And like my kids would
call me that or tell me I'm glazing
right now, but I I've really I mean uh
just like sincere thank you because I
I've been through this unsuccessfully
and I have leaned on the tool set, the
community so much as we go throughout
this and as I emailed you guys before
like helping developers make more money.
For me, what that means is I got to take
my kids to Disney World. And before I
started building, like my wife and I
were down to zero. We had an incredibly
difficult infertility struggle and we
spent everything to get our kids here.
And then we're looking at ourselves
like, do we sell the house? We're never
going to go on a vacation again until we
figure out something else because we're
like, we got the kids here and we're
super grateful, but it might not be
exactly what we wanted. And that story
has completely changed because of this
app and because of what Revenue Cat has
helped me with. So, thank you to the
entire team.
I think we get about 1% of the credit
for that. And we take about 1% of the
revenue. So, it's an even trade, you
know,
and I would call that a bargain.
What an incredible story. And and and as
you shared, like it wasn't a straight
path. It wasn't a great rich quick.
There were some hard knocks along the
way. some really hard decisions, some a
lot of stress, but you pushed through
and and you came out the other side and
have built a really cool business. And
so, yeah, as Jacob said, and I'll say it
again, you know, congrats. It's
fantastic. You
thanks so much for listening. If you
have a minute, please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.